in this video we're going to look at how
to pay vendors in Dynamics GP and
compare that to the experience of paying
vendors in Dynamics 365 business
Central in my GP system I've created a
batch using my default payment option ID
that looks for outstanding invoices that
are due at the end of the month and any
available discounts since I've already
created my payment batch I can select
the edit payment batch button and then
view all the vendors and in voices that
have been selected to pay here is where
I can make any changes and choose to not
pay a certain vendor or certain
invoices now let's see how we can pay
vendors in business
Central Business Central allows you to
easily create payment journals and
suggest the vendors to pay based on
criteria you've defined similar to GP
let's take a closer look to create
vendor payments I'll click on the search
icon and type payment journals based on
the search results I can then select
payment
journal in my payment journals I can
select my general
batch under prepare I'll select suggest
vendor
payments similar to my payment option ID
in GP I can select previously saved
defaults that I don't need to re-enter
information each time I create vendor
payments the last payment date is how I
can indicate that we want to pay
invoices due on or before that date and
we've also indicated to include any
available payment
discounts now let's click okay and have
business Central suggest the list of
payments based on the criteria we've
entered in this list you can see the
system has created several payments for
my vendors I currently have the system
set up to create one payment per invoice
however in a moment we'll look at how we
can change that setting
here I can see the amounts of the
payments and the invoices they're
applied to now let's say we're a bit
cash strapped this month and it looks
like this payment run will come to about
$440,000 by using the vendor priority
functionality in business Central the
suggest payments will ensure that we're
paying our high priority vendors first
to see the vendor priority let's open up
a vendor
card in the vendor card I can go under
the payments area and see the priority
the lower the number the higher the
priority we see worldwide importers is
set to a priority
one now let's go back and run a payment
again paying only our high priority
vendors first I'm going to select all my
payments so that I can delete them and
then regenerate
them back under the suggest vendor
payments I'm now going to select the
option to use vendor priority I'm also
going to type in that we want to pay
20,000 towards our vendor invoices for
the month we will then choose to
summarize per vendor or create one in
one payment per
vendor now you can see the system has
reduced the number of payments to only
our Priority One
vendors through the use of vendor
priority and suggest payments business
Central has helped streamline pay
your most strategic vendors and giving
you better control of your cash flow